Priscila Santiesteban

Computer Science & Physics Major

in Priscila.Santiesteban
2246 S Linley Ct
Denver, Colorado 80219

✓pasantiesteban@coe.edu

Sustaining high success academically, a first-generation minority female student with experiences in varies coding software and languages; including Visual Studios, C++, and Java. Seeks to attend graduate school for computer science. Highly motivated to expand her skills.

Education

Coe College 2020

Bachelors of Art in Computer Science & Physics

Minor in Mathematics

GPA: 3.8

Software Languages

Python

Java

C++

C#

JavaScript C

Tech Skills

Visual Studio

Java Development Kit

Intellij

Github

BitBucket

TestComplete

QA Complete

Linux

Conference

NNCI REU

Convocation 2019

- Gave a Talk Regarding PARADIM REU research from Summer 2019 at Cornell University.
- Gave poster session.

MINK WINK 2019

 Conference guest at Northwestern University.

Languages

English Spanish

Work Experience -

REUSE Undergrauate Researcher

Carnegie Mellon University (May 2020 - July 2020) Christian Kastner: Research Adviser & Mentor

- Conducted an independent theoretical project on patch quality in automatic program repair.
- Developed a patch ranking program that would rank patches based off of number of state and control flow changes in Java.
- Varviz and Symbolic Execution tools were used to analyze patches generated.
- Analysis of the ranked sample patches proved effectiveness of patch ranking method and algorithm

PARADIM Undergradute Researcher

Cornell University (June 2019 - August 2019) Nicole Benedek: Principle Investigator & Mentor

- Conducted an independent research project examining the link between anomalous mechanical and thermal properties in crystals
- Applied Density Functional Theoretical simulations to examine the structure and chemistry of certain materials using LINUX and QuantumEspresso
- Published a scientific report to the PARADIM and CNF REU website of Cornell University regarding summer research
- Gave a recorded oral presentation and poster talk at the 2019 NNCI REU Convocation at Cornell University

Teacher Assistant of Computer Science

Coe College Computer Science (February 2019 - May 2019) Stephen Hughes: Computer Science Professor

- Efficiently assisted Professor Hughes in educating and tutoring first-year students in computer science learning Python by helping them accomplish lab work and homework
- Improved understanding and skills in Python

Software Engineer Intern

LimoLink (September 2018 - February 2019) David Weidner: Senior Software Designer

- Efficiently developed and debugged programs before deadlines, while working well with a team or independently
- Became proficient in C# and Javascript
- Quickly and accurately learned how to use new applications used in IT and QA such as TestComplete and BitBucket
- Improved problem solving and communication skills by learning to use several resources to solve issues

Resident Assistant Coordinator

Coe College Residence Life (August 2018 - May 2021) Ryan Pratt: Area Coordinator

- Promoted from resident assistant to assistant area coordinator who managed resident assistants of the female resident hall at Coe College.
- Prepared presentations and meetings for residence life training
- Assisted the Area Coordinator of the building in enforcing policies during the COVID pandemic
- Helped resident assistants adjust to COVID campus initiative and maintain relationships with their residents

Student Involvement & Honors

Clark	M	е	ri	t
Schola	rs	h	ij	O

One-Year Full Tuition Scholarship (May 2020)

 Awarded one-year full tuition scholarship for leadership, merit, and academic success at Coe College

Richard C. and Jennifer H. Hunt

Prize (May 2020)

 Award for showing high academic achievement in Computer science at Coe College

Sigma Pi Sigma Physics Honor Society

Physics National Honor Society (May 2020 - Present)

• Recognition for physics students who show academic excellence in physics at a GPA hgiher than 3.8

Physics Club Secretary

Physics Club (August 2019 - September 2020)

- Manages meetings and emails for Physics Club
- Took part in educating middle school students in basic python code with the Women in Stem Club
- Participated in the Regional Science Olympiad Competition for public schools as a judge

Outstanding Freshman In CS

Award (May 2018)

• Award for outstanding freshmen in computer science at Coe College

Arthur Wright Erskine Physics

Prize (May 2018)

Award for outstanding freshmen in physics at Coe College

Alpha Lambda Delta Honor Society

Academic National Honor Society (May 2018 - Present)

• For freshmen whose GPA exceeds 3.7

Relevant Courses Taken

Relevant Courses Taken ————————————————————————————————————				
Refevant Courses Taker				
Computer Science I - Fall 2017	2017 • 2018 •			
Computer Science II - Spring 2018 Calculus II - Spring 2018	2010	Foundations of Computer Science - Spring 2018		
Calculus III - Fall 2018	2019	Data Structures & Algorithms - Fall 2018		
Object Oriented Programming - Spring 2019 Electromagnetism - Spring 2019	2019	Foundations of Advanced Mathematics - Spring 2019		
Robotics and Advanced Electronics - Fall 20: Operating Systems - Fall 2019	19 2020 -	Quantum Mechanics - Fall 2019		
	2020			

Differential Equations - Spring 2020

Programming Languages - Spring 2020

Database Systems and Data Management - Spring 2020

Mathematical Modeling - Fall 2020 Classical Mechanics - Fall 2020 Net-Centric Computing - Fall 2020